[ WIND BLOWING ]
[ DOOR UNLOCKING ]
- Sir ? - I should like to see Miss Usher .
I 'm afraid that 's not possible , sir .
Miss Usher is confined to her bed .
- She is ill ? - Yes , sir .
- Is it serious ? - Sir ?
My name is Philip Winthrop .
Miss Usher and I are engaged to be married .
I cannot admit you , sir .
You cannot ?
- By whose order ? - Mr. Roderick , her brother .
- He has expressly forbidden ... - Well then I should speak to him .
I insist you announce me .
Yes , sir . You 're our guest . Come in .
Your coat , sir .
If you 'd just follow me .
Yes ? What is it ?
Your boots , sir .
- What about them ? - Do you mind ... taking them off ?
Taking them off ? What on earth for ?
I am sure Mr. Roderick will explain it to you , sir .
A strange request .
This is the first time I 've ever been ...
Sir .
If you 'd care to put these on , sir .
Thank you
And if we may go now ...
This way , sir .
What is the meaning of this ?
I ... This is Mr. Winthrop , sir .
How dare you admit anyone into this house .
WINTHROP : I insisted , sir . I felt I had the right .
Well , we can 't talk out here .
RODERICK : Please , come in .
- I gather you know who I am . - If you 'd please ...
[ WHISPERING ] Mr. Winthrop ... softly .
An affliction of the hearing .
Sound of any exaggerated degree
cut into my brain like knives .
My apologies .
I 'm afraid you are going to leave , Mr. Winthrop .
I 've come to see Madeline .
That is quite impossible She is confined to her bed .
Mr. Usher , your sister and I are betrothed .
- It was a mistake . - I don 't believe that .
Please , don 't argue with me , sir .
You must leave this house now .
It is not a healthy place for you to be .
[ LOUDLY ] Mr. Usher ...
I have ridden all the way from Boston to see Madeline
and I do not intend to leave without seeing her . Now , if ...
WOMAN 'S VOICE : Philip .
Madeline ...
Madeline , in Heaven 's name , you must return to your bed .
You came all the way just to see me ?
Yes , to see you .
Madeline , I must insist .
- We shall talk later , Philip . - Mr. Winthrop is leaving .
- Leaving ? - I 'm not leaving .
He must stay , Roderick .
Please , let him stay , Roderick .
Very well , he will stay .
Now , for pity 's sake , return to your bed
RODERICK : What happened ?
I think your fireplace needs the screen .
Does it ?
I was just admiring this painting here .
- Is it your own work ? - It is .
And ... you also play this lute .
I do .
Mr. Winthrop , are you actually planning to marry my sister ?
Mr. Usher
during the time we spent together in Boston ...
it never occurred to me ...
And I dare say to Madeline neither
That we were not destined to each other .
When she left me she said to me : " I will love you forever " .
Does it seem so incredible that I would want to marry her ?
If you only knew how incredible .
And I suppose this vision
includes children ?
God willing ...
God willing ?
If you knew the nightmare you are picturing for me , sir ...
- Nightmare ? - That 's what I said .
Why shouldn 't Madeline marry and have children ?
Because the Usher line is tainted , Mr. Winthrop .
- Tainted , sir ? - You saw Madeline and you see me .
We are dying , Mr. Winthrop .
As you saw her today she is and she will remain ...
Believe me , sir ... I bear you no malice .
Were things otherwise
I should welcome to our family joyously .
But under the circumstances it is quite impossible .
But why do you assume that
you are dying ?
There are many reasons .
Pray , give me one then .
Madeline and I are like figures of fine glass .
The slightest touch and we may shatter .
Both of us suffer from a morbid acuteness of the senses .
Mine is the worst , for having existed along and the both of us are inflicted with it .
Any sort of food
more exotic than the most pallid mashes
unendurable to my taste buds .
Any sort of garment other than the softest
is agony to my flesh .
My eyes are tormented by all ...
but the faintest illumination .
All these assail me constantly
as I 've said ...
the sounds of any degree whatsoever inspire me with terror .
That 's why your servant asked me to remove my boots .
Yes . And even so I could hear you coming .
Every footstep . Every rustle of your clothes .
I could hear your horse approaching .
Hear the clatter of the hoofs across the courtyard .
Your knock !
The grating of the door bolt was like a sword struck to my ears .
I can hear the scratch of the rat claws within the stone wall .
Mr. Winthrop , three quarters of my family
have fallen into madness .
And in their madness they have acquired a superhuman strength
so that it took the power of many to subdue them .
Do you not exaggerate , sir .
[ PLAYS CHORDS ]
Perhaps there have been in your family certain
peculiarities of temperament , but ...
Peculiarities of temperament ?
How diplomatically you put it !
Peculiarities of temperament .
[ STRUMS LUTE ]
Would you permit me to light a candle so that ... ?
I think you had better leave , Mr. Winthrop .
I think you need some light in this house , Mr. Usher .
Two pale drops of fire
clattering in the vast , consuming , darkness .
My sister and myself .
Shortly they will burn no more .
She cannot leave this house , Mr. Winthrop .
Believe that or not as you will , but she cannot leave it .
For her own sake as well as yours , will you leave now , please .
No , I will not .
Very well .
Bristol will show you to a room .
I warned you , sir .
Whatever consequences may follow your refusal to leave ,
are upon you alone .
[ HOUSE SHAKING ]
[ KNOCKING ON DOOR ]
Yes ?
BRISTOL : Supper , Mr. Winthrop .
- I 'll be down directly . - BRISTOL : Very good , sir .
[ HOUSE CREAKING ]
[ HOUSE RUMBLING ]
- What is that noise ? - What happened ?
- Is it Mr. Winthrop ? - Philip ! .
- I 'm all right , Madeline . - What happened ?
- I 'm not sure . - Philip , you 'd better leave this place .
Please leave ! It isn 't safe for you .
Darling , I 'm all right .
I 'm not leaving you , Madeline .
- Mr. Winthrop ? - No , thank you .
My dear ?
You haven 't touched the thing , Madeline .
[ HOUSE CREAKS ]
Don 't you think
that crack in the wall should be repaired ?
For future generations of Ushers ?
For Madeline 's safety .
It was probably the trembling of the house which caused ...
that chandelier to fall .
Do you really think so ?
Have you a better explanation ?
While I was riding here , I noticed a singular lack of vegetation in the area .
Is there something wrong with the soil ?
The soil ? Yes , of course .
- Roderick , please . - As you will .
- How do things go in Boston , Philip ? - Everyone asks for you .
Do they ?
We miss you , Madeline . We all miss you .
[ RODERICK PLAYING LUTE ]
Remarkable . And you composed it yourself ?
Yes .
May we have another ?
I 'm afraid Madeline must retire now .
But I am not tired .
Very well .
Good night , brother .
Good night , my dear .
Good night , Philip .
Good night .
I suggest we retire too , Mr. Winthrop .
Gladly .
I trust that you will be prepared to leave tomorrow morning .
If you wish ... But if I do
I won 't be alone .
I intend to see that ...
[ MUFFLED GASP ]
- [ WHISPERING ] Oh , Philip - Darling .
I 'm sorry I frightened you .
I did not want your brother to hear .
Philip , I missed you .
I love you .
Madeline , I swear to you , tomorrow you leave this place with me .
- If only I could . - You will , you will .
You don 't understand .
But you 've never seen the heart of this horrible house .
Darling , once you 're with me you 'll wake up from this ... this nightmare !
[ DOOR SLAMS ]
Good night , sir .
Mr. Usher , perhaps you fail to understand ...
You cannot order my life , Roderick .
Is it so easy for you to forget , Madeline ?
- My life is my own . - Is it ?
Yes .
- I think that ... - Is it , Madeline ?
You hate me so much you want to keep me a prisoner here ?
Hate you ?
Oh , my dear , hate you ?
Don 't you know that I love you more than anything in the world ?
Can 't you see it 's my love for you makes me act as I do .
You cannot leave here , Madeline .
You know what would happen if you did , you know that .
- I know what you 've told me . - Oh , my dear .
Do not delude yourself , I beg of you , do not delude yourself .
- Sir ... - I shall stay with her .
In the name of God , would you not understand ! Leave my sister be .
Mr. Usher , I mean to take her from this house tomorrow .
I will not argue with you . Will you leave , please ?
[ PHILIP ] We 'll be all right , Madeline .
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ HOUSE CREAKING ]
[ CLANGING , RUMBLING ]
[ DOOR HINGE CREAKING ]
Madeline ?
[ WIND GUSTING ]
[ DOOR SLAMS ]
[ CLANG ]
[ CLANGING ]
[ CREAKING ]
Madeline ?
[ WHISPERING ] Don 't touch her !
You mustn 't wake her , sir .
The shock could be very harmful .
- [ PHILIP ] How did she get here ? - Se walks in her sleep , sir .
And then she comes here ?
She is obsessed by thoughts of death . Poor child !
How long has she been doing this ?
Ever since her return from Boston , sir .
I 'll just take her to her room .
- No , I ... - No !
NO , NO .
You might awaken her , sir .
Better let me .
I 've done it before .
- Good morning , Bristol . - Good morning , sir .
Has Miss Madeline had her breakfast yet ?
Oh , no , sir .
Good , then I 'd like to take her breakfast straight to her .
Very well , sir . Of course , she does not eat very much usually
- Well then we will see that she does eat . - Yes , sir .
- All right , let 's see what we have here ... bread , that 's good ...
Milk ? A little fruit ?
- Why , I 'll take it to her , sir . - No , I 'll do it .
- Yes , sir . - Oh , how about some eggs ?
No , sir . I think perhaps a little gruel .
It 's the most she has ever eaten in the morning .
- Gruel ? - Yes , sir .
Oh , yes , her sense of taste .
Well , all right then , hot gruel ... for both of us .
Yes , sir .
How long have you been with the Ushers , Bristol ?
Sixty years , sir .
- Sixty years ? - Ever since I was a boy .
Why then this is as much your house as it is Mr. Roderick 's .
And Miss Madeline , sir .
Not after today .
I 'm taking her to Boston with me .
We 'll see .
[ CRACKING ]
How long has that been going on ?
So long I 'm hardly aware of it any more .
It 's just the settling of the house .
That settling can cause this entire structure to collapse .
- And that doesn 't worry you ? - Oh , no , sir .
If the house dies , I shall die with it .
Be careful , sir . It was about to hit you .
It could cause a nasty burn .
It 's that fissure that causes the entire house to shake .
Yes , sir .
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
Who is it ?
Your breakfast , Miss Usher .
Hot gruel and ... hot gruel .
It 's so dark in here I can barely see you .
There .
[ SIGH ] No sunlight .
There 'll be sunlight where we leave .
Now ... good morning .
Good morning .
If he comes in now don 't be afraid .
He won 't come in . He has to take drugs to sleep
Oh , I 'm sorry .
Well now ...
We 'll fill you with hot gruel and good cheer !
You 're so sweet to me .
Nothing too good for future Mrs. Winthrop .
- Mrs. Winthrop ? - Open your mouth .
I 'm not hungry .
Madeline , I have no scrawny woman I my home , now open your mouth .
Come on .
Madeline , get ready to leave .
- I want to , Philip . - Then you will .
- I can 't . - Why ?
Because very soon I shall be dead .
I forbid you to say that ever again .
- It is true , Philip . - It is not true , Madeline .
You 're full of life .
Look at me , Philip . Do I look full of life ?
I remember you as you were in Boston .
Do you remember ? You were exuberant .
You were filled with the joy of living .
And so you 'll be again when you leave here and become my wife .
I wish you could understand .
Let me understand , Madeline , let me so that I can help you .
Perhaps you shall feel differently after you see .
[ DOOR CREAKS OPEN ]
- Where are we going ? - You 'll see .
Careful , darling .
- You don 't want to go in there . - I want you to see .
Put your weight against it .
[ DOOR CREAKS ]
The all our ... Ushers .
It 's the lack of air in here .
It 's the air itself .
Nothing can survive that long .
My great-grandfather .
His wife .
My grandfather .
My grandmother .
My father .
My mother .
This is monstrous !
Whose idea was this ? Your dear brother 's ?
There is one for him too .
Does that absolve him ?
It waits for me .
No , it does not .
They all wait for me .
Madeline , Madeline , you must stop this .
Can 't you see what you are doing to yourself ?
You don 't understand .
I understand , but you must leave the dead to themselves .
Madeline , come away with me now .
[ SCREAMS ]
What have you done ?
Give her to me .
- Thank you . See to the crypt , will you ? - Yes .
Well , are you content now , Mr. Winthrop ?
It is not I who forced her to live in the cemetery .
Do you think that I wish her harm ?
I think you still do not understand .
And I think it 's time that you did .
The tarn is very deep .
One of the Usher women drowned herself in it .
She was never found .
I dare say it 's deep enough to swallow this house entire .
I 'm waiting , Mr. Usher .
Last night you asked me about the singular aridity
of the land around this house .
Once this land was fertile , farms abounded .
Earth yielded her riches at harvest time .
There were trees and plant life , flowers . Fields of grain .
There was great beauty here .
At that time this water was clear and fresh .
Swans glided upon its crystal surface .
Animals came to its bank , trustingly , to drink .
But this was long before my time .
Why do you tell me these things ?
And then something crept across the land and blacked it .
The trees lost their foliage .
The flowers languished and died .
Shrubs grew brown and shrivelled .
The grain fields perished .
And the lakes and ponds became black and stagnant .
And the land withered as before a plague .
A plague ?
Yes , Mr. Winthrop , a plague of evil .
RODERICK : Anthony Usher , thief , usurer
merchant of flesh ...
Bernard Usher . Swindler , forger .
Jewel thief . Drug addict .
Francis Usher ... professional assassin .
Vivian Usher . Blackmailer
harlot , murderess .
She died in a madhouse .
Captain David Usher
smuggler , slave trader ... mass murderer .
Mr. Usher , I don 't see that this has anything to do with Madeline and myself .
I don 't believe in the sins of the fathers being
visited upon the children .
You do not , Sir ?
The house of Usher seems to you , then , normal ?
The house , Sir , is neither normal nor abnormal .
It 's only a house .
You are very wrong , Mr. Winthrop .
This house is centuries old . It was brought here from England .
And with it every evil rooted in its stones .
You really believe this ?
Evil is not just a word .
It is reality . Like any living thing
it can be created and was created by these people .
The history of the Ushers
is a history of savage degradations .
First in England , and then in New England .
And always in this house .
Always in this house .
Born of evil which feels , it is no illusion .
For hundreds of years , foul thoughts
and foul deeds have been committed within its walls .
The house itself is evil now .
No , I ... I cannot believe this .
But you must .
For Madeline 's sake , you must .
Most of all , does this evil reside in her .
And this is your dreadful secret ?
Mr. Winthrop ...
Do you think those coals jumping from the fire out to you
were an accident ?
Do you think that chandelier falling was an accident ?
Do you think that falling casket was an accident ?
Are you trying to tell me that the house
made those things happen ? - Yes .
No , Sir , that 's ridiculous , but even if it were true
even if this house were full of evil ...
Madeline is not .
Not for all of your talk are you .
You cannot take my sister out of this house .
If she were to wed and bear children
the Usher evil would spread and you , malignant cancer ...
- You are mad , I will not listen to you . - She will .
No , I will not !
PHILIP : I 'll tell you what 's evil in this house , Sir . You !
I will not let your sicken fancies
destroy Madeline 's life .
She leaves with me today .
[ KNOCKING ]
Who is it ?
We 're leaving . Now .
Madeline , you have no other choice .
If you remain here , this house will destroy you .
Then , you know .
I know that your brother 's poisoned you with his absurdities .
This entire atmosphere of sickness and disillusion is his doing .
Oh Madeline , believe me , there 's nothing wrong with you that
leaving this house won 't cure .
Do you love me ?
- You know I do . - Then leave with me now .
I will .
Well , pack just a few belongings . I 'll get my things ready .
- How we go ? - You 'll ride with me .
Later on we get coach to Boston .
Oh , Philip , can it truly be ?
Darling , within an hour , within an hour we 'll be away form here .
I love you .
Pack , quickly !
MADELINE 'S VOICE : No , I will not let it happen any longer .
Now please let me go . I don 't care what you say !
You can 't keep me .
And I will go .
No , I will not let you . Please let me go .
- I say I will ! - Madeline !
I must leave , Roderick . Please let me .
Madeline !
I don 't care what you say .
- There 's nothing you can say to me , Roderick . - Madeline , open the door .
[ MADELINE SCREAMS ]
What have you done to her ?
Madeline ?
No ...
Yes , she is dead .
I told you she could never leave this house .
- What did you do to her ? - I didn 't touch her .
You killed her !
There 's no mark on her . You are the one who killed her .
I told you she was not well , and yet you persisted .
Her heart cannot withstand the strain you put upon her .
That 's no matter now .
At least she has been spared the agony of trying to escape .
One candle left to burn now
before the darkness comes .
At least
she has found peace now .
Has she ?
Why do you say that ?
Because I do not believe that for the Ushers
there is peace hereafter .
Is there no end to your horrors ?
No , non whatever .
For they are not mine alone .
Mere passage from the flesh cannot undo centuries of evil .
There can be no peace without penalty .
Then you wanted her to die .
- Wanted ? - Yes !
I did not wish her death .
I only knew it was inevitable
as my death is inevitable .
Our blight must be removed from this earth .
What lies beyond is something else again .
Must you close it now ?
She must take her place below with the rest of the Ushers .
One last look .
I cannot bear to look at her .
- I 'll carry her with you . - Bristol and I can manage .
I would rather if you don 't mind .
I 'll carry her .
Come .
[ MADELINE BREATHING ]
[ MADELINE SCREAMS ]
I just wanted to say goodbye .
Shall I prepare some breakfast before you leave , Sir ?
- No , thank you . - Some coffee , then ?
- Yes , a little bit . - Very good , sir .
- Shall I serve it in the ... ? - No , no , I 'll take it here .
You look tired , Sir .
I don 't suppose any of us slept much last night .
No , Sir .
- Bristol . - Yes ?
Do you think it was my coming that caused Miss Madeline to ... ?
Oh , no Sir , not at all .
- Miss Madeline was not well . - Her brother thinks I killed her .
It 's just that he is highly overwrought , Sir .
- Yes , thank you for the coffee . - Your welcome , Sir .
Don 't recriminate yourself , Mr. Winthrop .
Miss Madeline 's passing was not your fault .
She was very weak , poor child .
It was ... the Usher blood .
There 's been such a history of illness in the family .
What with heart ailments , nervous diseases , catalep ...
And the like , Sir . Miss Madeline was ...
- What did you say ? - Sir ?
- You said catalepsies ? - Did I , sir ?
Was Madeline subject to cataleptic trances ?
- Oh no Sir , not Miss Madeline . - The truth ! Was she ?
No Sir !
That 's why Mr. Usher wanted to put her in the crypt so soon .
Oh , no Mr. Winthrop .
Oh my god !
No , you are wrong , Sir ! You 're wrong !
Sir !
BRISTOL : Mr. Winthrop !
- Leave her in peace , Sir . - Peace ?
Leave her in peace , Sir .
Don 't Sir ! I beg of you .
- Where is she ? - I don 't know , Sir .
- Tell me ! - I don 't know , I swear I don 't know .
I thought she was here .
You knew she was alive .
- I wasn 't sure , Sir . - You weren 't sure ?
[ GROANS ]
Sir !
Usher !
[ DOOR OPENS ]
What do you wish ?
Where is she ?
So you know .
Where ?
You cannot find her .
- Tell me where she is . - In a secret place .
- For the last time ... - Go on , you will be doing me a
very great favour . Go on .
- Where is she ? - Don 't touch me !
- Where is she ? - Dead .
You lie ! You buried her alive !
I did ... but she is dead now .
- I swear it . - You swear it ?
- You buried your own sister alive ? - But I had to do it .
Can 't you understand that ? She was doomed !
Where is she ? Where is she ?
- Where is the secret place ? - Secret ?
- Bristol , you must know . - I know nothing , Sir .
I 'll find her .
- Sir , was it necessary to ... - You know that it was .
Please , Sir . Try to get some rest .
- I 've got to find her . - But it 's too late , Sir .
- No ! - Please , Sir . Please .
- She is alive . - Try to get some rest .
I know she is ... she is alive .
[ VOICES FAINTLY WEEPING ]
[ VOICES LOUDER ]
[ SILENT SCREAMING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ WOMAN SCREAMS ]
[ THUNDER ]
[ WINDOWS CLANGING ]
[ LUTE PLAYING ]
[ THUNDER ]
[ DOOR OPENS ]
Still here ?
I suggest you leave , Mr. Winthrop .
No ? Then perish with us .
[ THUNDER ]
The old house crumbles ...
Perhaps this storm will finish it .
You have murdered your sister , Mr. Usher
and I intend to see that you hang for it .
Do you ?
Arrange it quickly , then .
If only I could kill you myself .
- Yes , if only you could . - Yes .
[ THUNDER ]
Why did you do it ?
I told you .
Shh .
You will never understand
this so logical mind as yours I have committed to murder .
If you only knew the agonies I have spared you in the world .
If you only knew the agonies I have endured in your behalf .
Did you know ... ?
[ THUNDER ]
Do you know that I could hear every sound she made ?
That I heard her breathing in her casket ?
Heard her first gasps as she awoke ?
Her first scream of terror ?
Did you know that I could hear the scratching of her fingernails
on the casket lid ?
You are mad !
Be done !
- What ? - Nothing , I rave .
You said , " Be done ! " , what did you mean ?
Nothing .
- Is she still alive ? - No .
- Is she ? Is she ? - Yes !
Yes , even now I hear her .
- No ... - Yes ... alive .
Deranged ... infuriate ...
Can you not hear her voice ?
Where ? In the name of god , where ?
Below . Twisting ... turning
scratching at the lid with bloody fingernails .
Staring , screaming , wild with fury , the strength of madness in her .
Can you not hear her voice ? She calls my name ...
Roderick !
[ THUNDER ]
MADELINE 'S VOICE : Roderick !
[ SCRATCHING ]
Where is she ?
MADELINE 'S VOICE : Roderick !
No ...
- Give me this . - RODERICK : Wait .
Don 't go down there .
Let her die .
[ CREAKING ]
She has the madness .
[ MADELINE 'S VOICE CRYING OUT ]
[ MADELINE CRYING OUT ]
BRISTOL : Mr. Winthrop , please .
- Leave her , Sir . - Leave her ?
But you may never find her .
The house is honeycombed with secret passages .
She could be anywhere , Sir .
- I 'll find her . - But she is mad , Sir .
[ BREATHING HARD ]
[ THUNDER ]
[ VOICES CRYING FAINTLY ]
[ HINGE CREAKS ]
[ THUNDER ]
[ WOMAN SCREAMING ]
Madeline !
BRISTOL : Mr. Winthrop !
Mr. Winthrop .
Mr. Winthrop , please .
Mr. Winthrop , you must leave .
- Where is she ? - Outside walls began to crack .
- Where has she gone ? - I don 't know . I beg of you , please .
The whole house may at any moment ...
[ MADELINE SCREAMS ]
Madeline ... No ... .
Madeline ...
[ SCREAMS ]
There was no other way . There was no other way ...
[ VOICES CRYING ]